

Chie Hayashida

First name: Chie Email address: chie8842@gmail.com

Last name: Hayashida **Web:** https://chie8842.github.io/ab

outme/



Software engineer with extensive knowledge of **DWH architectures**, **ML pipelines** and **infrastructure engineering**. Designed and Developed **many types of systems** which includes both BtoB and BtoC systems in **9+ years** of experience. Combines **technical skills**, **creativity** and **leadership** to empower the business from an engineering point of view. Has excellent **presentation skills** and self motivative enough to learn new technologies, **contribute to OSS** and **write technical articles**.



Work experience

Google Strategic Cloud Engineer(Data & Analytics)
Tokyo

12/2019 - present

Cookpad.Inc Tokyo **Software Engineer**

11/2017 - 11/2020

- Leads the development of search and recommendation for Cookpad itself and new businesses in all processes of designing and evaluating KPI, make and managing strategic plans, implementation, in terms of NLP and machine learning.
- Develops tools to simplify machine learning deployment and maintenance.
- Builds **AutoML** function using table data for recipe data normalization.
- Makes technical presentations at several conferences and write technical articles for recruitment and awareness improvement.

Ubie.Inc Tokyo **Freelance Engineer**

12/2018 - 01/2019

Built ChatOps System for Kubernetes deployment with Golang.

Retty.Inc Tokyo **Data Engineer**

03/2017 - 10/2017

- Launched and led the data engineering team and solved problems of current DWH.
- Built the basis of data utilization environment using Apache Spark, BigQuery, fluentd, kinesis, Airflow and embulk in a short period of time.
- Led infrastructure configuration management in AWS and GCP environments using **Terraform** and **Ansible**.

NTT Data Corporation Tokyo **Software Engineer**

04/2010 - 04/2017

- Designed and developed data processing and recommender algorithms for the TV program recommendation system using Hadoop and Spark (global system, 4000+ nodes).
- Conducted PoC of data processing for exhaustion prediction of car parts using sensor data.
- Contributed to Apache Hadoop, Apache Spark, Apache Airflow, and so on
- Designed and implemented data transfer, backup and recovery procedures with a performance-oriented approach, in the BCP project of a huge and demanding mobile fee system.
- Took charge of everything **from network, OS to middleware design** for system development in the US of a Japanese company.
- Performed **root cause analysis** in response to a technical troubleshooting request for **Hadoop** and **Spark** from a customer with a support contract.
- Did troubleshooting about Oracle Database in several projects.
- Educated and mentored several engineers.

Education

Nara Institute of Science and Technology Nara Japan **MSc Engineering**

04/2008 - 03/2010

- Master thesis described Linear transformation approaches to many-to-one voice conversion.
- We made **8+ presentations** at domestic conferences and study groups.

Osaka University Osaka Japan **BSc Engineering**

04/2004 - 03/2008

- Learned about programming basics(C and C++), biotechnology, mathematical analysis, linear algebra, statistics, and mechanical engineering.
- Bachelor thesis described Measurement method of receptive field characteristics of primary visual cortex.





Languages



Certificates

Google	Google Cloud Professional Data Engineer	12/2020
AWS	AWS Solution Architect Associate	10/2018
IPA	Database Specialist Japanese IT Security Evaluation and Certification Scheme	04/2012
IPA	Network Specialist Japanese IT Security Evaluation and Certification Scheme	10/2012
IPA	Applied Information Technology Engineer Japanese IT Security Evaluation and Certification Scheme	04/2011

Achievements

- Won 1st prize in micro service tuning contest at AWS re:Invent2018 GameDay.
- Won 18th prize (Top 1%) in one week challenge at Kaggle PetFinder competition.
- A contributor and reviewer of TensorFlow document translation and ci tools of it.
- Develop and contributes some OSS includes TensorFlow, Apache Spark and so on.
- A (co-)organizer of several communities and meetups in Tokyo.
- Performed speeches at PyConJP, PyData London, Docker Meetup and so on.
- Writing technical articles in Gihyo Magagines.











Tennis

Piano